{
    "questionModals": [
        {
            "question": "Who gave the name 'Sagarmatha' to World's highest peak Mt. Everest?",
            "answers": [
              "Som Nath Sigdel",
              "Chakrapani Chalise",
              "Lekhnath Poudel",
              "BabuRam Acharya"
            ],
            "correctIndex": 3
          },
          {
            "question": "मनिसको शरीरमा सबैभन्दा लामो कोषिका ( Cell ) कुन हो ?",
            "answers": ["रक्त कोष", "स्नायु कोष", "हाड कोष", "माथिका सबै"],
            "correctIndex": 1
          },
          {
            "question": "सबैभन्दा बढी कार्बनडाइअक्साइड उत्सर्जन गर्ने मुलुक कुन हो ?",
            "answers": ["चिन", "अमेरिका", "बेलायत", "भारत"],
            "correctIndex": 0
          },
          {
            "question": "विश्व बैङ्कद्वारा सार्वजनिक प्रतिवेदन अनुसार सन् २०२४ मा नेपालको अर्थतन्त्र कति प्रतिशतले वृद्धि हुने अनुमान छ ?",
            "answers": ["३.३%", "३.६%", "२.९%", "४.१%"],
            "correctIndex": 0
          },
          {
            "question": "जनगणना २०७८ अनुसार शौचालयको पहुँच पुगेको जनसङ्ख्या कति रहेको छ ?",
            "answers": ["९१.३%", "९३.६%", "९५.५%", "९९.१%"],
            "correctIndex": 2
          },
          {
            "question": "दिगो विकास लक्ष्यको ‘5P’ भन्नाले के के बुझिन्छ ?",
            "answers": ["People,Planet,Prospirity,Peace,Partnership", "People,Problem,Prospirity,Peace,Partnership", "People,Problem,Prospirity,Peace,Position", "Psychology,People,Prospirity,Problem,Partnership"],
            "correctIndex": 0
          },
          {
            "question": "UNO को पहिलो विशिष्टीकृत संस्था कुन हो ?",
            "answers": ["UNDP", "UNESCO", "ILO", "World Bank"],
            "correctIndex": 2
          },
          {
            "question": "प्रत्येक महिलालाई सुरक्षित मातृत्व र प्रजनन स्वास्थ्य सम्बन्धी हक हुनेछ भनी कुन मौलिक हकमा व्यवस्था गरिएको छ ?",
            "answers": ["स्वतन्त्रताको हक", "महिलाको हक", "समानताको हक", "स्वास्थ्य सम्बन्धी हक"],
            "correctIndex": 1
          },
          {
            "question": "नेपाललाई कुष्ठ रोग मुक्त घोषणा कहिले गरियो?",
            "answers": ["वि.सं. २०3६ माघ १०", "वि.सं. २०४६ जेठ ५", "वि.सं. २०५६ असार १२", "वि.सं. २०६६ माघ ५"],
            "correctIndex": 3
          },
          {
            "question": "सूर्यका किरणमा भएको सबै रङ्हरुलाई मिसाउदा कुन रङ तयार हुन्छ ?",
            "answers": ["सेतो", "रातो", "कालो", "निलो"],
            "correctIndex": 0
          },
          {
            "question": "कार्यालयको महत्व तलका मध्ये कुन होइन?",
            "answers": ["जनसम्पर्क केन्द्र", "छलफल केन्द्र", "व्यवस्थापन केन्द्र", "अभिलेख केन्द्र"],
            "correctIndex": 1
          },
          {
            "question": "निजामती सेवा ऐन २०४९ को प्रकाशन कहिले भएको थियो?",
            "answers": ["वि.सं. २०४९ माघ ४", "वि.सं. २०४९ जेठ १०", "वि.सं. २०५० जेठ ४", "वि.सं. २०५० माघ १०"],
            "correctIndex": 2
          },
          {
            "question": "संघीय मामिला तथा सामान्य प्रशासन मन्त्रालयका हालका सचिव को हुन?",
            "answers": ["मुकुन्द प्रसाद निरौला", "भानुभक्त जाेशी", "कमल प्रसाद भट्टराई", "अश्विन कुमार पोखरेल"],
            "correctIndex": 0
          },
          {
            "question": "नेपालको संबैधानिक निकाय मध्ये कुन निकायको अधक्ष पदमा नियुक्त हुन अनिवार्य स्नाकोत्तर आवश्यक पर्दछ?",
            "answers": ["निर्वाचन आयोग", "लोकसेवा आयोग", "महिला आयोग", "दलित आयोग"],
            "correctIndex": 1
          },
          {
            "question": "सञ्चित कोषको सञ्चालन र जिल्लागत रूपमा राजस्व आम्दानी र बजेट खर्चको नगद व्यवस्थापन सम्बन्धी कार्य गर्न प्रयोग हुने TSA को पुरा रुप के हो",
            "answers": ["Treasury Simple Amount", "Transparent Second Amount", "Treasury Simple Account", "Treasury Single Account"],
            "correctIndex": 3
          },
          {
            "question": "राष्ट्रिय कर दिवस कहिले मनाइन्छ?",
            "answers": ["असार २०", "मंसिर १", "कार्तिक २९", "चैत २५"],
            "correctIndex": 1
          },
          {
            "question": "सुचनाको हकको संरक्षण, सम्वर्धन र प्रचलन गर्ने कामका लागि रहने सुचना आयोगको अध्यक्ष को रहने व्यवस्था छ?",
            "answers": ["प्रधानमन्त्री", "मुख्यसचिव", "सभामुख", "सुचना तथा सन्चार मन्त्री"],
            "correctIndex": 2
          },
          {
            "question": "सार्वजनिक सेवा बडापत्रको अवधारणाको विकास कुन देसबाट सुरु भएको हो?",
            "answers": ["बेलायत", "अमेरिका", "चिन", "जर्मनी"],
            "correctIndex": 0
          },
          {
            "question": "चुनावको लागि मतदान स्थल निर्माण गरिएको अवस्था र त्यँहा मतदान कार्य हुन्छ भने सो अवस्थालाइ कार्यालय भनिन्छ/भनिदैन?",
            "answers": ["भनिन्छ", "भनिदैन", "दुवै हुन सक्छ", "कुनै पनि हैन"],
            "correctIndex": 0
          },
          {
            "question": "राज्यका नीतिहरु नेपालको संविधानको कुन धारामा उल्लेख गरिएको छ?",
            "answers": ["धारा ४९", "धारा ५०", "धारा ५१", "धारा ५३"],
            "correctIndex": 2
          },
          {
            "question": "Which branch of geology involves the study of Earth's water resources, including groundwater and surface water?",
            "answers": ["Hydrogeology", "Oceanography", "Glaciology", "Climatology"],
            "correctIndex": 0
          },
          {
            "question": "Which era of the geologic time scale is known as the Age of Dinosaurs?",
            "answers": ["Cenozoic Era", "Mesozoic Era", "Paleozoic Era", "Precambrian Era"],
            "correctIndex": 1
          },
          {
            "question": "Wind erosion primarily shapes landscapes through the process of:",
            "answers": ["Abrasion", "Corrosion", "Freeze-thaw action", "Mass wasting"],
            "correctIndex": 0
          },
          {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a primary goal of structural geology?",
            "answers": ["Understanding the formation of mountains and valleys", 
            "Identifying potential sites for oil and gas exploration", 
            "Analyzing the causes and effects of landslides", 
            "Studying the behavior of glaciers"],
            "correctIndex": 3
          },
          {
            "question": "Which of the following primary structures is often used to determine the original top and bottom of a sedimentary sequence?",
            "answers": ["Joints", 
            "Veins", 
            "Graded bedding", 
            "Unconformities"],
            "correctIndex": 3
          },
          {
            "question": "The classification of foliation is based on:",
            "answers": ["Mineral composition", "Grain size","Orientation of mineral grains","All of the above"],
            "correctIndex": 2
          },
          {
            "question": "Which layer of the Earth is divided into several large and small tectonic plates?",
            "answers": ["Crust", "Mantle","Outer core","Inner core"],
            "correctIndex": 0
          },
          {
            "question": "Which depositional structure is characterized by alternating layers of fine and coarse sediment?",
            "answers": ["Ripple marks", "Graded bedding","Mud cracks","Cross bedding"],
            "correctIndex": 1
          },
          {
            "question": "Which sedimentary rock is primarily composed of rounded gravel-sized particles cemented together?",
            "answers": ["Sandstone", "Conglomerate","Mud rocks","Limestone"],
            "correctIndex": 1
          },
          {
            "question": "Which of the following symmetry elements indicates a rotation by 180 degrees about an axis?",
            "answers": ["2-fold rotation axis", "3-fold rotation axis","4-fold rotation axis","6-fold rotation axis"],
            "correctIndex": 0
          },
          {
            "question": "Which physical property of minerals describes their resistance to scratching?",
            "answers": ["Hardness", "Cleavage","Color","Luster"],
            "correctIndex": 0
          },
          {
            "question": "Which physical property of minerals describes their resistance to breaking, bending, or deforming?",
            "answers": ["Hardness", "Cleavage","Fracture","Tenacity"],
            "correctIndex": 3
          },
          {
            "question": "What phenomenon occurs when light waves interact with each other, resulting in the reinforcement or cancellation of certain wavelengths, leading to the appearance of different colors?",
            "answers": ["Dispersion", "Interference","Polarization","Birefringence"],
            "correctIndex": 1
          },
          {
            "question": "Which principle of stratigraphy states that layers of sediment are originally deposited horizontally, and any deviation from horizontal indicates subsequent deformation or tilting?",
            "answers": ["Law of Superposition", "Principle of Original Horizontality","Principle of Cross-Cutting Relationships","Principle of Faunal Succession"],
            "correctIndex": 1
          },
          {
            "question": "The stratigraphic unit that represents a specific period of time and is defined by its rock content and fossil assemblage is called:",
            "answers": ["Bed", "Member","Formation","Stage"],
            "correctIndex": 3
          },
          {
            "question": "Which mode of fossil preservation involves the replacement of organic material by minerals, resulting in a stone replica of the original organism?",
            "answers": ["Permineralization", "Carbonization","Petrification","Recrystallization"],
            "correctIndex": 2
          },
          {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a phylum commonly represented in the fossil record?",
            "answers": ["Mollusca", "Chordata","Echinodermata","Insecta"],
            "correctIndex": 3
          },
          {
            "question": "Which chemical classification of igneous rocks is based on the percentage of silica (SiO2) present in the rock?",
            "answers": ["Ultramafic", "Mafic","Intermediate","Felsic"],
            "correctIndex": 3
          },
          {
            "question": "Which metamorphic rock exhibits a silky or wavy appearance due to the alignment of its mineral grains?",
            "answers": ["Slate", "Phyllite","Schist","Gneiss"],
            "correctIndex": 1
          },
          {
            "question": "Which process involves the concentration of minerals through the mechanical sorting and accumulation of heavy minerals in sedimentary environments?",
            "answers": ["Sedimentation", "Sublimation","Bacteriogenic concentration","Mechanical concentration"],
            "correctIndex": 3
          },
          {
            "question": "Which prospecting criteria focuses on the study of rock types and their associations with mineralization?",
            "answers": ["Structural-tectonic", "Lithological","Stratigraphical","Magmatogenic"],
            "correctIndex": 1
          },
          {
            "question": "Porosity of soil refers to:",
            "answers": ["The volume of void spaces in soil relative to its total volume", "The weight of soil per unit volume","The ratio of air to water content in soil","The cohesion between soil particles"],
            "correctIndex": 0
          },
          {
            "question": "Cohesive soil exhibits:",
            "answers": ["Strong internal cohesion due to the presence of clay minerals", "Weak internal cohesion due to the presence of sand and gravel","High porosity and low void ratio","High degree of saturation and low permeability"],
            "correctIndex": 0
          },
          {
            "question": "Rock strength is a measure of",
            "answers": ["The resistance of a rock to weathering", "The ability of a rock to support heavy loads without deformation","The maximum stress a rock can withstand before failure","The degree of fracturing and discontinuities within a rock"],
            "correctIndex": 2
          },
          















    ]
}